Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我叫Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we are going to be talking about the weather.
今天我们要谈论天气。
That's right.
没错。
And you know, Marco, this is a really, really useful and important topic in English, isn't
你知道，Marco，这在英语中是一个非常、非常有用的重要话题，不是吗？
it?
是吗？
Exactly, because if you ever travel abroad, you always want to know about the weather,
没错，因为如果你出国旅行，你总是想知道天气情况，
right?
对吧？
That's right.
没错。
And Anglo people, English people, all they ever do is talk about the weather.
而且盎格鲁人、英国人，他们整天做的就是谈论天气。
Well, it's an important topic.
嗯，这是个重要的话题。
You want to know what clothes to wear or if you should take an umbrella.
你想知道该穿什么衣服，或者是否该带伞。
Or even when you're making small talk with people.
或者当你在和别人闲聊时。
Exactly.
没错。
So we are going to be taking a look at the weather in the United States.
所以我们要看看美国的天气。
But before we get started with the dialogue, let's take a look at vocabulary preview.
但在开始对话之前，我们先来看看词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Okay, so we have two words we're going to hear in the dialogue.
好的，我们有两个词会在对话中听到。
Now the first one is forecast.
第一个是forecast。
Forecast.
Forecast。
Weather forecast.
天气预报。
So this is what we listen to or what we see on the television, the weather forecast.
这就是我们听或看电视上看到的天气预报。
Right, it's like the prediction of the weather.
对，就像对天气的预测。
Okay, so forecast, can I only use it in the weather?
好的，那么forecast，只能用在天气上吗？
No, of course you can use it in many other different situations, like in business, for
不，当然你可以在很多其他不同情况下使用它，比如在商业中，
example, forecast sales.
例如，预测销售额。
Okay, so the prediction of sales.
好的，所以是对销售额的预测。
Very good.
非常好。
And we have one more word on vocabulary preview, a shower.
词汇预览中还有一个词，shower。
A shower.
A shower。
Shower.
Shower。
So when it rains for a short time and it's not too heavy, that's a shower.
所以当下雨时间短且不太大时，那就是阵雨。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So it's very similar to a shower at home.
所以这和家里的淋浴很相似。
Right.
对。
A little bit of water.
一点点水。
And it doesn't last too long.
而且不会持续太久。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue now.
那么我们现在为什么不听听对话呢？
We are going to be listening to the weatherman as he describes the weather in Utah.
我们要听天气预报员描述犹他州的天气。
And now let's go to Kenny Williams for today's weather forecast.
现在让我们连线Kenny Williams，带来今天的天气预报。
Thank you, Bill, and good morning, Salt Lake City.
谢谢，Bill，早上好，盐湖城。
What's the weather looking like today, Kenny?
今天天气怎么样，Kenny？
Well, it's a bit of a mixed bag in Utah today.
嗯，今天犹他州的天气有点复杂。
We've got heavy cloud cover here in northern Utah, and we're calling for scattered showers
犹他州北部有厚厚的云层，我们预计全天有零星阵雨，
throughout the day, with a daytime high of 45 degrees.
白天最高气温45度。
Now, if we move down to the south of the state, we can see that a cold front is moving in.
现在，如果我们往南移动，可以看到一股冷锋正在逼近。
We can expect clear skies, but it will be quite cold, with temperatures hovering around
我们可以期待晴朗的天空，但会很冷，气温徘徊在
the 30 degree mark.
30度左右。
It's a chilly day, folks, so don't forget your coats.
今天很冷，各位，别忘了带外套。
What about tomorrow, Kenny?
明天怎么样，Kenny？
Do you have good news for us?
你有好消息给我们吗？
Well, it'll be a rainy day for northern Utah.
嗯，犹他州北部将是雨天。
We can expect some isolated downpours in the morning.
我们预计早上会有局部暴雨。
Winds will be coming in from the northeast, with gusts reaching 23 miles per hour.
风将从东北方向吹来，阵风达到每小时23英里。
Salt Lake City can expect the rain to turn to sleet in the evening.
盐湖城预计晚上雨会变成雨夹雪。
Things are looking a bit better for the south.
南部的情况会好一些。
We'll see cloudy skies with a chance of showers.
我们会看到多云天气，有可能有阵雨。
Later in the day, we can expect partly cloudy skies with a forecast high of 38 degrees.
白天晚些时候，我们预计部分多云，预报最高气温38度。
You heard it, folks.
你们都听到了，各位。
It's going to be a cold one.
天气会很冷。
That's right, Bill.
没错，Bill。
We'll have more later on today on the 6 o'clock news.
我们会在今天的6点新闻中提供更多信息。
That's the weather forecast for this morning.
这是今早的天气预报。
All right, so we listened to the weather forecast and it doesn't seem like nice weather in Utah,
好的，所以我们听了天气预报，看起来犹他州的天气不太好，
huh?
是吧？
No, it certainly doesn't.
不，确实不好。
I don't think that I'd really like to live there.
我觉得我不会真的想住在那里。
Well, maybe it's winter or something like that.
嗯，也许是冬天之类的。
Well, I guess, yeah, maybe it's good for skiing.
嗯，我想，是啊，也许适合滑雪。
Okay, so now I think it's time for us to take a look at some of those maybe difficult words
好的，所以现在我认为是时候看看一些可能比较难的词了，
that we may have listened to in this dialogue in Language Takeaway.
我们在对话中可能听到的那些，在语言要点部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, here we're going to look at some words and phrases that you can use to describe
好的，这里我们要看一些可以用来描述天气的单词和短语。
the weather.
天气。
Now, the first one, we heard in the weather forecast that they were calling for scattered
第一个，我们在天气预报中听到他们预报有零星阵雨。
showers.
零星阵雨。
Scattered showers.
Scatter.
零星的。
Scattered, if something is scattered.
零星的，如果某物是零星的。
It's sort of like it's a little bit of that thing everywhere.
它有点像到处都有那么一点。
Okay, so and we already talked about what showers were.
好的，我们已经讨论过什么是阵雨。
Right, so shower is a small amount of rain.
对，所以阵雨是少量的雨。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
To better understand when something is scattered, imagine that we are in a playground and the
为了更好地理解什么是零星的，想象我们在一个操场上，
children are playing in the playground.
孩子们在操场上玩。
So the children are scattered everywhere.
所以孩子们到处散落。
Some of them are playing on the swing.
有些在荡秋千。
Some of them are playing on the grass or in the sandbox.
有些在草地上或沙坑里玩。
So children, a little bit of children in every different spot.
所以孩子们，每个不同的地方都有一点孩子。
So if we think that the city is a playground, maybe in one part of the city there's a little
所以如果我们把城市想象成一个操场，也许城市的一个地方有一点雨，
bit of rain but not in the other part.
但另一个地方没有。
Exactly.
没错。
That's a scattered shower.
那就是零星阵雨。
Very good.
非常好。
Moving on to our second word, we have hovering.
继续到第二个词，我们有hovering。
Hovering.
Hovering。
Temperatures hovering around the 30-degree mark.
气温徘徊在30度左右。
The temperature is hovering around.
气温在徘徊。
Okay, so when I say the temperatures are hovering.
好的，所以当我说气温在徘徊。
You mean it's approximately.
你的意思是大约。
Okay, so they can move up and down.
好的，所以它们可以上下波动。
So maybe it'll be a little bit warmer than 30 degrees or a little bit colder.
所以可能比30度稍微暖和一点或稍微冷一点。
Yes.
是的。
So if you think of hovering as floating.
所以如果你把hovering想象成漂浮。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So why don't we listen to some more examples of how we could use hovering in different
那么为什么我们不听听更多关于如何在不同的情况下使用hovering的例子呢？
situations.
情况。
Example 1.
例子1。
Government rates are hovering around the 10% mark despite the government's attempts to
尽管政府试图刺激经济，政府利率仍徘徊在10%左右。
stimulate the economy.
刺激经济。
Example 2.
例子2。
The waiters kept hovering around us all night.
服务员整晚都在我们周围徘徊。
It was really annoying.
真的很烦人。
Example 3.
例子3。
The company's margin this year is hovering around the 40% mark.
公司今年的利润率徘徊在40%左右。
Okay, so pretty clear.
好的，很清楚。
Hovering is sort of floating around one area.
Hovering有点像在一个区域周围漂浮。
Very good.
非常好。
Now, let's move on to the next part.
现在，让我们继续下一部分。
We saw that we're going to have isolated downpours.
我们看到会有局部暴雨。
Isolated downpours.
局部暴雨。
Okay, let's break this one down.
好的，我们来分解一下。
Let's start with downpour.
先从downpour开始。
A downpour is when you have a lot of rain, very strong rain.
Downpour是指有很多雨，非常大的雨。
That's right.
没错。
For maybe a short amount of time, it's really raining heavily.
可能持续很短时间，但下得很大。
Right.
对。
So that's what a downpour is.
所以这就是downpour的意思。
And if we take a look at the first word, isolated.
如果我们看第一个词，isolated。
So in one small area.
所以在一个小区域里。
Okay, confined it to a specific area.
好的，限制在特定区域。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so we have an isolated downpour.
好的，所以我们有局部暴雨。
It'll be raining in one specific area.
会在一个特定区域下雨。
And you hear this a lot with weather language.
你在天气语言中经常听到这个。
You hear isolated showers, isolated snow storms.
你会听到局部阵雨、局部暴风雪。
Exactly.
没错。
So it'll be in a specific area only.
所以只会在特定区域。
All right.
好的。
So along with these showers and rain, we also talked about wind.
所以除了这些阵雨和雨，我们还谈到了风。
And we heard that we will have gusts reaching 23 miles per hour.
我们听到会有阵风达到每小时23英里。
So we're going to have gusts reaching 23 miles per hour.
所以会有阵风达到每小时23英里。
Gusts of wind.
阵风。
Okay, so can you explain to our listeners what gusts are?
好的，你能向我们的听众解释一下什么是阵风吗？
Okay, so a gust is a sudden increase in the amount of wind.
好的，阵风是风速的突然增加。
Okay, so maybe we'll have normal wind and all of a sudden it will get really windy.
好的，所以也许有正常的风，然后突然变得风很大。
That's right.
没错。
For a short amount of time.
持续很短时间。
Okay, that's a gust.
好的，那就是阵风。
G-U-S-T, gust.
G-U-S-T，gust。
Gust of wind.
阵风。
And for our final word on Language Takeaway today, we're going to have sleet.
今天语言要点的最后一个词，我们要讲sleet。
Sleet.
Sleet。
All right, sleet is a terrible kind of weather.
好的，雨夹雪是一种糟糕的天气。
It's sort of a mixture between snow and rain.
它有点像雪和雨的混合物。
So sleet is kind of this strange mix between ice and rain and snow.
所以雨夹雪是冰、雨和雪之间的一种奇怪混合物。
So just imagine, it's not completely ice, so it's not solid, but it's not water, right?
所以想象一下，它不是完全的冰，所以不是固体，但也不是水，对吧？
It's not rain.
不是雨。
And it's not snow either.
也不是雪。
No, it's in the middle.
不，它在中间。
Okay.
好的。
All right, so sleet.
好的，所以是雨夹雪。
But what you really need to know is that it's terrible.
但你需要知道的是它很糟糕。
All right, so that's all the words we have today for Language Takeaway.
好的，这就是今天语言要点的所有单词。
Let's move on now to Fluency Builder.
现在让我们继续到流利度构建部分。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
All right, in Fluency Builder today, we're going to look at three phrases that are really
好的，在今天的流利度构建中，我们要看三个在谈论天气时非常常见的短语。
common when you're talking about the weather.
天气。
Now we heard in the dialogue that there was a cold front moving in.
我们在对话中听到有一股冷锋正在逼近。
A cold front moving in.
一股冷锋正在逼近。
A cold front is moving in.
Okay, so a cold front.
好的，所以冷锋。
Imagine a wall of cold air and it comes towards a place and then it changes the pressure in
想象一堵冷空气墙，它朝一个地方移动，然后改变大气压力。
the atmosphere.
大气压力。
Okay, so a very sudden amount of cold air that comes into a place.
好的，所以一股非常突然的冷空气进入一个地方。
Right.
对。
So we say a cold front is moving in.
所以我们说冷锋正在逼近。
So we always think of these cold fronts or warm fronts as moving.
所以我们总是认为这些冷锋或暖锋在移动。
So you can either say they're moving in or you can say a cold front is coming in.
所以你可以说它们正在逼近，或者说冷锋正在到来。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And okay, we have a cold front that's moving in and we're going to have winds that will
好的，有一股冷锋正在逼近，我们会有风从东北方向吹来。
be coming in from the northeast.
从东北方向吹来。
Okay, winds coming in from.
好的，风从……吹来。
So when I say it's coming in from.
所以当我说它从……吹来。
You're talking about its origin, where it starts.
你在谈论它的起源，它从哪里开始。
Okay, so if I change the noun and I don't say winds anymore but maybe I'll say my friends.
好的，所以如果我改变名词，不说风了，也许说我的朋友。
My friends are coming in from Chicago.
我的朋友们从芝加哥来。
So they are arriving from Chicago.
所以他们从芝加哥到达。
Exactly.
没错。
So what else can I say?
那么我还能说什么？
Or you can also say the kids are coming in from outside.
或者你也可以说孩子们从外面进来。
Okay, so where they were before.
好的，所以他们之前在哪里。
Very good.
非常好。
So coming in from.
所以从……进来。
You can change the noun a little bit and you can form these new sentences.
你可以稍微改变一下名词，然后就能组成这些新句子。
Great.
很好。
Now our final phrase.
现在是我们最后一个短语。
We heard the announcer say it's going to be a cold one.
我们听到播音员说“it's going to be a cold one”。
It's going to be a cold one.
今天会很冷。
So I have this phrase, it's going to be a cold one.
所以我有这个短语，“it's going to be a cold one”。
What do I mean by a cold one?
我说“a cold one”是什么意思？
Okay, so the one represents the event.
好的，所以这个“one”代表事件。
Of the day.
这一天的。
Okay, so it's going to be a cold day.
好的，所以意思是今天会很冷。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
Now we can obviously change the adjective, right?
现在我们显然可以改变形容词，对吧？
So it's going to be a hot one, it's going to be a long one, it's going to be a long
所以可以说“it's going to be a hot one”、“it's going to be a long one”、“it's going to be a long
day.
一天”。
Alright.
好的。
But the one can mean anything.
但这个“one”可以指任何东西。
Okay, so it can be a day, it can be an event.
好的，所以它可以指一天，也可以指一个事件。
A meeting.
一次会议。
Okay.
好的。
A project.
一个项目。
So for example, if we're going to a meeting, I might say, hey Marco, this is going to be
所以举个例子，如果我们去开会，我可能会说，嘿，Marco，这会是一场
a hard one.
艰难的会议。
Okay, so the one represents the meeting.
好的，所以这个“one”代表会议。
That's right.
没错。
A hard meeting.
一次艰难的会议。
Alright, I think this is a very good phrase and it's very commonly used, so why don't
好的，我认为这是一个非常好的短语，而且非常常用，所以我们不如
we listen to some more examples of how we can use it's going to be a something one.
再听一些例子，看看如何使用“it's going to be a something one”。
Example one.
例子一。
Temperatures are forecasted to hit 37 degrees today.
今天预计气温将达到37度。
It's going to be a hot one, folks.
各位，今天会很热。
Example two.
例子二。
It's only 8am and I've got a hundred emails already.
才早上8点，我已经收到一百封邮件了。
It's going to be a long one today.
今天会是漫长的一天。
Example three.
例子三。
I haven't studied at all for the exam.
我考试一点都没复习。
It's going to be a tough one.
这次考试会很难。
Okay, so some great examples and I think it's time for us to listen to this dialogue again
好的，这些例子很棒，我想是时候再听一遍这段对话了，
and now we can understand all these words and phrases that we've just talked about.
现在我们可以理解我们刚刚讨论的所有这些单词和短语了。
And now, let's go to Kenny Williams for today's weather forecast.
现在，让我们连线Kenny Williams，带来今天的天气预报。
Thank you Bill and good morning Salt Lake City.
谢谢Bill，早安，盐湖城。
What's the weather looking like today, Kenny?
今天天气怎么样，Kenny？
Well, it's a bit of a mixed bag in Utah today.
嗯，今天犹他州的天气有点复杂。
We've got heavy cloud cover here in northern Utah and we're calling for scattered showers
犹他州北部有厚厚的云层，我们预计全天有零星阵雨，
throughout the day with a daytime high of 45 degrees.
白天最高气温45华氏度。
Now, if we move down to the south of the state, we can see that a cold front is moving in.
现在，如果我们往南移到州南部，可以看到一股冷锋正在逼近。
We can expect clear skies, but it will be quite cold with temperatures hovering around
我们可以期待晴朗的天空，但会很冷，气温徘徊在
the 30 degree mark.
30华氏度左右。
It's a chilly day, folks, so don't forget your coats.
各位，今天很冷，所以别忘了带外套。
What about tomorrow, Kenny?
明天呢，Kenny？
Do you have good news for us?
有好消息吗？
Well, it'll be a rainy day for northern Utah.
嗯，犹他州北部会是雨天。
We can expect some isolated downpours in the morning.
我们预计早上会有局部暴雨。
Winds will be coming in from the northeast with gusts reaching 23 miles per hour.
风将从东北方向吹来，阵风可达每小时23英里。
Salt Lake City can expect the rain to turn to sleet in the evening.
盐湖城预计晚上雨会转为冻雨。
Things are looking a bit better for the south.
南部的情况会好一些。
We'll see cloudy skies with a chance of showers.
我们会看到多云天气，有阵雨的可能。
Later in the day, we can expect partly cloudy skies with a forecast high of 38 degrees.
当天晚些时候，我们预计部分多云，最高气温38华氏度。
You heard it, folks.
各位，你们听到了。
It's going to be a cold one.
今天会很冷。
That's right, Bill.
没错，Bill。
We'll have more later on today on the 6 o'clock news.
我们会在今晚6点的新闻中带来更多消息。
That's the weather forecast for this morning.
这是今早的天气预报。
Okay, so we know that in English-speaking countries, the weather is always, always,
好的，所以我们知道在英语国家，天气总是、总是、
always a great subject of conversation for small talk, right?
总是闲聊的好话题，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
If you ever want to talk to somebody or start a conversation, the weather is always the
如果你想和别人聊天或开始对话，天气总是
number one topic.
头号话题。
Yep.
是的。
And we actually have a phrase in this dialogue that would be great for starting a conversation.
而且这段对话中实际上有一个短语非常适合用来开始对话。
Like for example, imagine if you lived here in Utah and you were, you know, wanting to
比如，想象一下如果你住在犹他州，你想
start a conversation with someone, you could say, it sure is a cold one today, isn't it?
和某人开始对话，你可以说，“今天真冷，是吧？”
Exactly.
没错。
That's a great way of starting a conversation and English-speaking people love to talk about
这是开始对话的好方法，正如你所说，英语国家的人喜欢谈论
the weather, as you say.
天气。
That's right.
没错。
So, guys, if you have any questions about weather vocabulary or if you want to practice
所以，各位，如果你们对天气词汇有任何疑问，或者想练习
talking about the weather, come to our website at EnglishPod.com.
谈论天气，请访问我们的网站EnglishPod.com。
Right.
对。
Erika and I are always there to answer any questions or doubts you may have.
Erika和我随时在那里回答你们可能有的任何问题或疑惑。
And also, if you have any stories about crazy weather maybe in the countries you're from,
另外，如果你们有关于你们国家疯狂天气的故事，
let us know.
请告诉我们。
So, thanks for downloading, you guys, and until next time, goodbye.
所以，感谢你们的下载，各位，下次再见，拜拜。
Bye.
拜拜。